<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Museum of Science and Industry, Chicago</string>

    <string name="fast_forward_tour">Fast Forward(&#8230;) Inventing the Future</string>
    <string name="future_energy_tour">Future Energy Chicago</string>
    <string name="science_tour">Science Storms</string>
    <string name="u505_tour">U-505 Submarine</string>

    <!-- Information for the exhibits in the Fast Forward tour. -->
    <string name="cantu_info">Chef Homaro Cantu was executive chef at Moto Restaurant as well as an
        innovator looking to take the dining experience to a new level through design and
        engineering. Cantu filed numerous patents covering diverse fields such as dining items,
        cookware and edible surfaces. Cantu has also worked with NASA to develop a
        "food replicator"—a converted ink-jet printer that produces edible prints. On display in the
        exhibit is a case that he used to conceal his patent-pending process for printing edible
        paper, as well as some of his innovative utensil designs. Throughout his work, Cantu looked
        for ways to help people: to change the way we feed people in crisis, disseminate medicine
        to stem an epidemic, sustain astronauts on long missions and more. He believed his work with
        the West African “miracle berry,” which alters how your taste buds perceived sweet and sour,
        could help diabetics, people in regions where available food is edible but bitter or bland,
        and those whose ability to taste has been affected.
    </string>
    <string name="de_grey_info">Trained as both a computer scientist and a biologist, Aubrey de Grey
        is conducting biological research in order to radically extend the human life span. He is
        the founder of the Methuselah Mouse Prize, a scientific competition designed to draw
        attention to the ability of new technologies to slow and even reverse the damage of the
        aging process.
    </string>
    <string name="despommier_info">Dickson Despommier is leader of the visionary Vertical Farm
        Project, which proposes to grow food in high-rise buildings in urban centers, helping to
        feed increasing urban populations while also allowing sprawling farmland to be returned to
        nature. Inside the gallery, guests will see a large scale model of Despommier\'s vertical
        farm concept and also play an interactive game that will teach them more about the
        possibilities of urban agriculture.
    </string>
    <string name="diamandis_info">As chairman and CEO of the X-Prize Foundation, Peter Diamandis
        offers prizes of $10 million or more for projects that benefit humanity. He is also CEO of
        Zero Gravity Corporation, a commercial space company that launches FAA-certified parabolic
        weightless flights for the general public using a Boeing 727 aircraft. More recently, he
        co-founded the Rocket Racing League, a hybrid of Indy car racing and rocket-powered flight.
    </string>
    <string name="howard_info">Ayanna Howard is associate professor and founder of the
        Human-Automation Systems (HumAnS) Lab at Georgia Institute of Technology. Her goal is to
        make robots better at helping people—better at not only gathering information, but also
        evaluating it. Her work at NASA\'s Jet Propulsion Lab includes the SmartNav Mars rover,
        which is designed to be more independent in its explorations of the Red Planet. As well,
        her trio of Snomote rovers will collect data in regions of extreme temperatures like
        Antarctica, which will help develop solutions to climate change. A model of a Snomote rover
        is on display.
    </string>
    <string name="johnson_info">Lonnie Johnson is best known as the rocket scientist who invented a
        toy—the Super Soaker® Water Gun—and he has more than 100 patents in his name. In Fast
        Forward, you can see Johnson\'s first prototype for the Super Soaker, made from a used water
        bottle, some plastic tubing and duct tape. With his start-up companies, Excellatron Solid
        State and Johnson Electro-Mechanical Systems, Johnson is now developing thin film batteries
        for cell phones and aerospace applications.
    </string>
    <string name="jorda_info">Sergi Jordà is part of the Music and Technology Group at the Pompeu
        Fabra University in Barcelona, where he directed the development of the Reactable, a
        multi-user, interactive, improvisational electronic musical instrument, now used in musician
        Björk\'s world tour. The instrument offers seemingly infinite musical possibilities, and you
        can try your hand at making music with Jordà\'s Reactable in the Fast Forward gallery.
    </string>
    <string name="kamkwamba_info">It only took 20-year-old William Kamkwamba a library book, some
        blue-gum trees, discarded bicycle parts and an inspired idea to become a sensation in his
        home country. Kamkwamba, who lives in a small African village in Malawi, began building
        windmills at age 14, after he had to drop of out high school because his family could not
        afford the tuition of $80 a year. Now his family has three windmills on their property,
        supplying power to their home for the first time. Since then, Kamkwamba has offered his
        assistance to others, helped build a windmill for his local school and worked on powering
        his entire village.
    </string>
    <string name="maisonnier_info">For over twenty years, Bruno Maisonnier was convinced that robotics
        would be the next revolutionary technology. In 2005, utilizing skills he developed working
        in the IT and banking industries, Bruno followed his dream and founded Aldebaran Robotics
        to produce autonomous humanoid robots that can contribute to the well-being of humans. The
        NAO robot created by Aldebaran is used in hundreds of labs and universities in over 30
        countries for cutting-edge research in robotics, artificial intelligence and computer
        science as well as sociology and medicine. See a NAO on display in the Fast Forward gallery.
    </string>
    <string name="simpson_info">Zack Simpson believes that art can be both playful and
        thought-provoking. Using unique technologies incorporating the entire body, a broad
        knowledge of science and a long history of game development, his company Mine-Control turns
        viewers into participants and teaches them something along the way. He is also a fellow at
        the Center for Systems and Synthetic Biology at University of Texas-Austin. In Fast Forward,
        experiment with Simpson\'s Mariposa, a wall projection interactive, to watch as butterflies
        land on your shadow.
    </string>

    <!-- Information for the exhibits in the Fast Forward tour. -->
    <string name="future_house">Play the role of an energy consultant as your team explores a
        virtual house, inside and out, to find energy savings.</string>
    <string name="future_neighborhood">Try urban planning: arrange homes, schools and businesses to
        minimize commutes and maximize efficiency.</string>
    <string name="future_car">Be tomorrow\'s automobile engineer: modify options like engine types
        and body materials to see energy savings.</string>
    <string name="future_power">As power engineers, your team selects sources to meet energy demand,
        cut pollution and stay on budget.</string>
    <string name="future_transportation">Create a transit network of buses, trains and bike paths to
        reduce traffic, link destinations and improve city life.</string>

    <!-- Information for the exhibits in the Science Storms tour. -->
    <string name="avalanche_info">Avalanches—or flows of granular material—offer stunning examples
        of how forces such as friction and gravity can act on an object, affecting its motion. Watch
        patterns of cascading granules change as you adjust the speed of the rotating Avalanche
        Disk. Find the right angle and velocity needed to launch a tennis ball projectile into a net
        across the exhibit hall. Repeat Leonardo da Vinci\'s friction studies for yourself, conduct
        Galileo's inclined plane experiment, and observe the fascinating "Brazil nut effect."
    </string>
    <string name="atoms_info">Atoms are the basic building blocks of matter, and determine the
        properties and behaviors of all materials. Experiment with amazing substances like shape
        memory alloy and ferrofluid to discover why their atomic arrangements make them behave the
        way they do. Take a virtual journey into the history of atomic theory. Get your hands on a
        virtual chemistry set: choose elements from a digitally projected periodic table, and then
        drag them across the tabletop to combine them and see what compounds can be made.
    </string>
    <string name="lightning_info">A lightning strike can inspire emotional reactions like few other
        phenomena in nature. While we\'ve learned much since the earliest lightning experiments,
        there\'s still plenty to discover about electrical charges and magnetism. Witness dramatic,
        high-voltage lightning as you sit below a large Tesla coil. Use electromagnetism to launch a
        ring 30 feet in the air, and build and propel a maglev train car that floats over the track,
        thanks to magnetism.
    </string>
    <string name="fire_info">Fire is a chemical reaction that has fascinated humans for millennia.
        Get up close to fire to investigate how fuel, oxygen and heat combine to create a flame.
        Test virtual sources of combustion to see what common and unusual substances can be used to
        power cars and rockets. Use the “flame test” to create colorful fireworks with chemicals
        that burn in vibrant colors. And learn how fires in nature can sometimes be helpful and
        sometimes harmful, and what tools we use to manage them.
    </string>
    <string name="sunlight_info">Sunlight takes just over eight minutes to reach us from the sun,
        and brings plenty of heat, energy and color on the trip. Follow the lead of curious
        scientists and identify, harness and study the properties of this abundant resource.
        Sunlight streams through the Museum’s roof so that you can split white light into colors to
        recreate Isaac Newton’s prism experiments, focus the sun’s energy through a Fresnel lens to
        heat a liquid, and convert it into power to race model cars.
    </string>
    <string name="tornado_info">From palm trees in a typhoon to pinwheels on a blustery day,
        watching air in motion can be hypnotic. In its most powerful forms, wind can also devastate
        in a matter of moments. In the centerpiece of Science Storms, you\'ll be blown away by the
        tornado, a 40-foot vortex of swirling air and vapor you can study and manipulate. Nearby,
        you can also create convection by heating the air inside large balloons and observe the
        effect with thermal cameras. Or team up with friends to ride along with storm chasers in a
        virtual race to intercept severe weather.
    </string>
    <string name="tsunami_info">A wave is energy being moved from place to place through a medium
        such as air or water. Discover the power and motion of waves and their fundamental
        properties. You can design your own wave by choosing variables like wavelength and
        amplitude, and then launch it down the length of a 30-foot wave tank. Generate waves in
        round ripple tanks to watch them interact with objects or other waves. Stand below a
        20-foot-tall rope that oscillates as you vary the amplitude and frequency to produce a
        striking, interactive light sculpture, revealing the art within waves.
    </string>

    <!-- Information for the exhibits in the U-505 Submarine tour. -->
    <string name="the_u505_exhibit_info">The historic submarine now resides in an amazing indoor
        exhibition showcasing the story of its capture and exploring the technology and living
        conditions aboard the vessel.
        \n
        \n
        With multiple interactive units, archival media, videos narrated by Bill Kurtis and nearly
        200 artifacts, the U-505 Submarine exhibit is a treasure trove of history as well as a
        National Historic Landmark.
    </string>
    <string name="restoration_info">A typical German sub was built to last four years. Fifty years
        of turbulent Chicago weather may have proven to be the U-505\'s most brutal enemy. Indeed,
        left untreated and outdoors, it would have been unsafe for tours by 2004. And so, in 1997,
        the Museum launched the largest exhibit conservation project in its history—to preserve the
        U-505 and move it indoors to a climate-controlled environment.
        \n
        \n
        A large crew spent five months welding, cleaning, repairing and painting the hull.
        Brackets, stringers and ribs were re-manufactured using original construction drawings
        recovered from Germany and the patterns from badly eroded parts. It was difficult to find
        the sub\'s original color. The Museum conservation team used photos, a German archive
        painting manual, veteran recollections and more, so the sub could be conserved
        authentically. Ballast by ballast, tank by tank, the team installed reinforcements,
        focusing on jacking points and cradle locations. Ultimately, it took more than two years
        to ensure that the U-505 was structurally sound.
    </string>
    <string name="interactives_info">Aboard a re-created sub environment, climb through the hatch
        and experience the sights, sounds and feel that was reality for the U-505\'s 59 sailors
        during wartime.
        \n
        \n
        Try to maneuver in the sub\'s tiny galley, or kitchen, only big enough for one person to
        stand. Or take your turn in one of the sub\'s "hot bunks." Only 35 bunks were on board the
        U-505, and at the time of the vessel's capture, there were 59 sailors. This meant that most
        of the men had to "hot bunk," or take turns sleeping in beds still warm from the use of a
        fellow crew member.
    </string>

</resources>
